Southworth-Dickinson Family Papers, 1792-2005
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES III: DICKINSON FAMILY
  - Generation 3
    - Mayotta Dickinson Caffee Southworth
      - Biographical information (Box 116, Folder 5)
      - Diary, 1904-08 (Box 116, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence
        - A - B (Box 116, Folder 7)
        - Arthur Caffee
          - 1904 - Apr 1905 (Box 116, Folder 8-11)
          - May - Dec 1905 (Box 117, Folder 1-8)
          - Jan - Jun 1906 (Box 118, Folder 1-7)
          - Sep 1906 - Apr 1908 (Box 119, Folder 1-10)
          - May 1908 - Feb 1910 (Box 120, Folder 1-6)
          - Mar 1910 (Box 121, Folder 1)
          - undated (Box 121, Folder 2-5)
          - Miscellaneous items concerning Arthur Caffee (Box 121, Folder 6)
        - Corning - U (Box 121, Folder 7-12)
        - W - undated (Box 122, Folder 1-3)
      - School writings (Box 122, Folder 4)
      - Newspaper clippings kept by Mayotta (Box 122, Folder 5)
      - Notebook, 1929-66 (Box 122, Folder 6)
      - Announcements (Box 122, Folder 7)
      - Photographs (Box 122, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous items (Box 122, Folder 9)
    - Arthur Caffee
      - Biographical materials (Box 122, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence and financial items, 1904-09, undated (Box 122, Folder 11-13)
      - Navy log, 1904-08 (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - Spencer Dickinson: correspondence (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - Elizabeth Hamlin Young Dickinson: correspondence (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Dwight Dickinson, Jr.: correspondence (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Edward F. Dickinson correspondence (Box 123, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Dickinson family items
    - Genealogical papers (Box 123, Folder 6-10)
    - Book of Psalms belonging to William Dickinson, undated (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - Bound book of photographs (Box 124, Folder 2)
    - Photographs and negatives (Box 124, Folder 3-6)
    - Miscellaneous items (Box 124, Folder 7)
    - Stowe-Fletcher Family
      - Manassah Stow Journal, 1810: hand-copied, circa 1922 1922 (Box 125, Folder 1)
      - Manassah Stow Journal, original and typescript copy 1825 (Box 125, Folder 2-3)
      - Manassah Stow Journal,typescript copy 1827 (Box 125, Folder 4)
      - John Stow (Box 125, Folder 5)
      - Adolphus Fletcher (Box 125, Folder 6)
      - Sarah Maria Stow Fletcher (Box 125, Folder 7)
      - Lucy Fletcher Hawley (Box 125, Folder 8)
      - The Garland, 1840-41 (Box 125, Folder 9)
      - The Olio, 1848 (Box 125, Folder 10)
      - The Telegram, 1840 (Box 125, Folder 11)
      - Fletcher Family newspaper clippings (Box 125, Folder 12)
      - Scrapbook, containing Dickinson-Stowe Family items (Box 126)
- SERIES IV. BROWNE FAMILY
  - Correspondence
    - Lucy Mitchell Browne, 1882-98 (Box 127, Folder 1-9)
    - Dottie Mitchell "Dart" Hoffman, 1878-95 (Box 127, Folder 10)
    - Lucy Serena Croghan Browne, 1887-1906 (Box 127, Folder 11)
    - Lucy Mayotta Browne Hoffman, 1893-98, undated (Box 127, Folder 12)
    - Nina Florence Browne Craven, 1882-98, undated (Box 127, Folder 13)
    - J. Mitchell Browne, undated (Box 127, Folder 14)
    - John Dietrich Hoffman, 1892 (Box 127, Folder 15)
    - Spencer Edward Dickinson, 1894-98 (Box 127, Folder 16)
    - Charles Hoffman, 1893 (Box 127, Folder 17)
    - Kate McDougal, 1893, undated (Box 127, Folder 18)
    - Kate B. Mix, 1897, undated (Box 127, Folder 19)
    - Unsigned and undated Browne family (Box 127, Folder 20)
    - Estate information
      - Elana Browne Bishop (Box 127, Folder 21)
      - Evelyn Browne Hoffman (Box 127, Folder 22)
    - Browne Family miscellany (Box 127, Folder 23)
    - J. Ross Browne materials (Box 127, Folder 24-26)
    - J. Ross Browne materials (Box 128, Folder 1-6)
    - Browne family photographs (Box 128, Folder 7-8)
    - Browne family photographs (Box 129, Folder 1-10)
- SERIES V: DEANE FAMILY
  - John Deane (Box 130, Folder 1)
  - Rebecca to Melvin Deane correspondence, 1835-62, undated (Box 130, Folder 2-12)
  - Melvin G. Deane
    - Diary, 1847 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Letters of introduction (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1835-53
      - A - M (Box 131, Folder 3-14)
      - N - W (Box 132, Folder 1-3)
    - Miscellaneous writings, 1830s (Box 132, Folder 4)
  - Sarah Edwards Shepard Deane letter, undated (Box 132, Folder 5)
  - John G. Deane
    - Biographical materials, undated (Box 132, Folder 6)
    - Clippings about 6th Maine Civil War battery, undated (Box 132, Folder 7)
    - Diary, 1863 (Box 132, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1859-68, undated (Box 132, Folder 9-20)
    - Hymn book, Jun 1863 (Box 132, Folder 21)
- SERIES VI. SOUTHWORTH MANUFACTURING COMPANY RECORDS
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous financial records (Box 132)
    - 1839 - Jun 1842 (Box 133, Folder 1-15)
    - Jul 1842 - Dec 1843 (Box 134, Folder 1-12)
    - Jan - Oct 1844 (Box 135, Folder 1-9)
    - Nov 1844 - Jun 1845 (Box 136, Folder 1-7)
    - Jul 1845 - Jun 1846 (Box 137, Folder 1-7)
    - Jul 1846 - Jul 1847 (Box 138, Folder 1-10)
    - Aug 1847 - 1855 (Box 139, Folder 1-13)
    - 1856-74 (Box 140, Folder 1-11)
    - 1875-76 (Box 141, Folder 1-12)
    - 1887- Jun 1891, undated (Box 142, Folder 1-8)
    - Jul 1891 - 1899 (Box 143, Folder 1-10)
    - 1900-08 (Box 144, Folder 1-8)
    - 1909 - May 1913 (Box 145, Folder 1-9)
    - Jun 1913 - 1914 (Box 146, Folder 1-8)
    - 1915-16 (Box 147, Folder 1-9)
    - 1917-23 (Box 148, Folder 1-12)
    - 1924-29 (Box 149, Folder 1-8)
    - 1930-41 (Box 150, Folder 1-2)
  - Account books, 1839-69 (Box 150, Folder 3-6)
  - Directors meetings minutes and company by-laws (Box 150, Folder 7-8)
  - The Southworth Story: The History of Southworth Company, 1839-1989 by Terry Spencer/Spencer Associates (Box 150, Folder 9-10)
  - Ledgers
    - 1837-39 (Box 151)
    - 1837-68 (Box 152)
    - 1839-51 (Box 153)
    - 1840-53 (Box 154)
- SERIES VII. MISCELLANEOUS MATERIALS
  - Correspondence, photographs, etc. (Box 155, Folder 1-9)
  - Genealogical information (Box 156, Folder 1-12)
  - Scrapbook (Box 157)
  - Ivorytype of unidentified child: broken original in sink mat and disks of "digital treatment images", [CLOSED. See Box 155, folder 6 for photographic reproduction. Digital image also available] (Box 158)